Abhilash Rajasekaran

Technical Support

Phone: +91-99406 18442 Email: lashabhi14@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To grasp a challenging position as Tech Support in a new or relevant domain, which gives me an opportunity to exhibit my technical skills and provides scope to enhance my knowledge and career.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

7 years of overall experience in Technical Support, Business Analyst, Quality Analyst and Team Handling. To seek and maintain a positionthat provoke professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, analytical skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills.

Good knowledge in team collaboration and working with Agile methodology using scrum, working experience in healthcare & supply chain domain. Passionate in the belief that business analysis and quality control is essential to the growth and success of an organization that wishes to scale and achieve higher levels of profitability. Ability to adapt to new environment quickly, strong team player, good communication, analytical skill, enthusiastic learner, confident, sincere, and committed.

SKILLS

- Client Interaction and Facilitation skills
- Business Analysis
- Gap Analysis
- Root Cause Analysis
- Training and Development
- Analytical thinking and problem solving
- Quality Audit and Monitoring
- Team Handling

TOOLS

- MS Office Tools.
- JIRA
- SQL (beginner)
- Mercury Gate
- Raptor
- Balsamiq

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Geodis India Private Ltd.,

Technical Support (April 2023 – September 2024)

- Analyze business requirements through tickets in Service Now and doing analysis to configure the expected outcome and achieve customer satisfaction.
- Interacting with business and internal users to determine the nature of the problems encountered and doing root cause analyses to resolve the same.
- Sharing technical updates through mail on recurring incidents which affect the internal and external process and communicating the same in team huddle.
- Troubleshooting the existing customer setup in case of issues, rectifying it, and doing an end-to-end resolution.
- Ensure smooth release in each implementation phase and testing the same.
- Handling issues related to carrier, customer and internal business users on Transportation ware housing and Yard Management Services.
- Identifying the issues on existing loads, purchase order, sales order, tender, contracts, shipment plan, customer invoicing.
- EDI/Email setup initiation for customer locations through Mercury Gate.
- Troubleshooting the existing Route Guide setup for each customer hierarchy and resolving the same.
- Implementing new lane setup for customers, along with accessorial specification, mode of transport and granting under the hierarchy.
- Doing smoke test through test environment before making an enhancement or implementation through different load.
- Working on setting up new user accounts and rectifying issues on existing accounts.
- Facilitate weekly meetings with clients and team to document requirements, scrum touch base and explore potential solutions.

Team Lead and Business Analyst AGS Health Private Ltd.,

Business Analyst (April 2017 - December 2020)

- Analyze client's business requirements and processes through document analysis, interviews, workshops, and workflow analysis.
- Liaise between business and technical personnel to ensure a mutual understanding of processes and applications.
- Participated in key meetings with clients including requirement sessions, system demos, and end-user training.
- Worked on process improvement opportunities to increase business efficiency by identifying trends. Collaborate, identify, and document existing business processes and workflows.
- Document, track, and provide updates on project status as well as participate in project planning andknowledge transfer sessions.
- Have the ability and consistency to work under pressure and adapt to changing business needs.

- Facilitate monthly meetings with clients to document requirements and explore potential solutions.
- Have experience in handling commercial and federal payers and providers.

Team Lead (January 2021 - September 2022)

- Mentored and guided employees to foster proper completion of assigned duties.
- Built strong relationships with customers through positive attitude and attentive response.
- Initiated timely response to client emails, queries, and escalations.
- Conducting team meetings and providing efficient feedback to users.
- Interacting with team in daily standup to discuss about sprint and reporting the same to Manager.
- Preparing weekly agenda to discuss the deliverables, pending items with the client and co-ordinate the meeting throughout the call.
- Sharing minutes of meeting after each discussion related to project and business with every lead associated to it.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in engineering (Electronics and CommunicationEngineering) 2012-2016

Sri Ramanujar Engineering College

Sri Ramanujar Engineering College Anna University. Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Abhilash Rajasekaran